Okay, so let's do the one method this
time.
So we're going to do the forward pass
using the one method.
Now remember with the one method now,
subsequent activities start the next day.
With a zero method, subsequent activities
start the same day.
Now subsequent activities start the next
day.
Now the basic difference
between zero and the
one method, basic
differences and similarities.
First of all, in both methods, critical
path is still going to be the same.
No change in the critical path.
Float values are still going to be the
same.
No change in float.
In fact, even the finish dates are still
going to be the same.
The early finish and late finish of each
activity is still going
to be exactly the same.
We will see that this project is still
finishing on day 19, same as before.
The only difference between the zero
method and the one method, the only
difference is that the late start and
early start, left inside of the boxes,
they're just going to be now increased by
one.
Now, in a separate video, we've got the
two methods side by side, comparing them
side by side, and I will explain what I
mean there when I say the early start,
late start, just going to be increased by
one, and we'll see it clearly there.
But that really is the only difference,
right?
Is that the early start and late start in
the zero method, all the activities,
they're just going to be increased by one.
And that is it, because they're starting
the next day.
And so the math is going to be slightly
different.
All right, so let's just go straight into
it then.
We're doing the one method.
A is a starting activity, so the early
start of A is going to be a one.
Now, we're calculating the early finish.
How did we calculate early finish before?
It was simply early start plus the
duration.
This time we have to minus 1.
In the 0 method, it was just early start
plus the duration.
But in the 1 method now, we have to
remember to minus 1.
So it's going to be 1 plus 2 minus the 1.
So we finish on day 2.
Again, we're still finishing on day 2,
same as we did before in the 0 method.
But this time we're finishing right at the
end of day 2.
Now, again, think logically.
If A finishes on day two, the next
activity that's dependent on A,
B, D and G, when do they start?
This time they start the next day.
So B, D and G will start on day three.
So they're now starting on day three.
They start the next day.
So it's kind of like plus one now.
And then when do they finish?
If you look at B, say math, it's going to
be early.
set up plus the duration minus the 1.
So for B, it's going to be 3 plus 4 minus
the 1, so it finishes on day 6.
For D, when does D finish?
3 plus 5 minus the 1, so it finished on
day 7.
G, 3 plus 6 minus the 1, so it finishes on
day 8.
So again, you always have to remember
minus 1 in this case.
So you can see now how the 1 method is a
little bit more challenging, because you
always always have to remember when
to plus one and when to minus one, right?
And if you plus one or minus one at the
wrong time, right, you plus one instead of
minus one and vice
versa, it throws off the
whole, you know, the whole calculations.
That's why the one method is a little more
challenging.
Now if you look at C here, B, finishing on
day six, so when do
we start C the next day?
Day seven, right?
So that's where we plus one.
So that's where this early finish is early
start plus duration minus 1.
But the early start of
the successor, the next
activity is early finish
of the current plus 1.
So successor then, C is a successor of B.
So C finishes on day 6, C will start the
next day, day 7.
7 plus 7 minus the 1 when to C finish,
day 13.
So now let's look at E.
E is dependent on D, D finish than day 7.
When do we start E the next day,
day 8?
When do we finish E?
8 plus 2 minus the 1, finish on day 9.
So now let's look at F.
F again, same principle as before.
F is dependent on B and E.
B finishes on day 6, E finished than day
9.
When do we start F?
Well, the earliest we can start F is when
E finishes.
E finishes on day 9.
So F will start the next.
day, day 10.
And then 10 plus 6, minus the 1 is 50.
Same with H.
H have a choice between 9 and 8.
E finishes on day 9, G finish on day 8.
So the early we can
start H is when E finishes
on day 9, but it starts
the next day, day 10.
And then 10 plus 7, minus the 1,
16.
And same with I then.
C finishes on day 13, F finishes on day
15, H finishes on day 16.
The earliest we can
start I is a later of the 3,
which is day 16, but it
starts the next day, day 17.
Oops, day 17.
Then 17 plus 3 minus the 1, 19.
And again, we're still finishing on day
19, same as before.
Whether you're doing
the zero method or the
one method, we're
still finishing on day 19.
The finish date is still going to be the
same.
Okay, so that was the first.
forward pass using the one method.